

## HemaSundar P

Lead Consultant



## **Professional Summary**

Enthusiastic Lead Consultant offering 10 years experience and expertise necessary to take on dynamic and complex software systems automation. Strong background in both manual and automation testing. Desire to bring abilities to new role with room for advancement.

Helps teams produce exceptional products by offering in-depth quality assurance support. Open and clear communicator with good multitasking skills, organized nature and strong attention to detail. Expert in Selenium, Java, Appium, Web services test automation & Jenkins.



## **Work History**

2015-03 -Current

#### Lead Consultant

XEBIA IT Architects Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, KA

- Helped multiple clients for setting up Test
   Automation environment and automating test
   cases by designing well-suited frameworks across
   multiple projects.
- Identified and Automated test cases using various frameworks like TestNG, Cucumber, Maven, etc.
- Scheduled Continuous Integration(CI) &
   Continuous Deployment(CD) pipelines for
   executing Automated test cases on several
   environments like on-premise server, Docker, AWS,
   etc using Jenkins.
- Operated under Agile and Scrum frameworks to complete releases every 2 weeks and wellorganized sprints.
- Created detailed automated test cases for use on diverse projects.
- Automated REST & SOAP Web Services testing



#### **Address**

Bengaluru, KA, 560067

#### **Phone**

+91-6361585259

#### E-mail

hpenugonda1988@gmail. com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/ in/hemasundarpenugond a/



Manual Testing

Java

Selenium WebDriver

Appium

**TestNG** 

Cucumber

Maven

**JIRA** 

**Jenkins** 

Docker

**AWS** 

Selenium Grid

Webservices Automation

SQL

using JAVA(Apache Http Components, Rest Assured) and SOAPUI respectively.

- Automated Android & iOS web and native apps using Appium.
- Worked across multiple domains like e-commerce, medical, retail, new, etc.

### 2012-10 -2015-02

## Senior Software Test Engineer

Trivium ESolutions Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, KA

- Conducted regression testing, analyzed results, and submitted observations to development team using JIRA.
- Created accurate and efficient test scripts in
   Selenium to manage functional automated testing of certain products and features.
- Implemented Hybrid Framework (Data-Driven & Keyword Driven) with TestNG, Maven, and Apache POI libraries
- Automated cross-browser testing using Selenium
   Grid.
- Reviewed requirements, specifications, and technical design documents to provide timely and meaningful feedback.
- Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality.
- Wrote and optimized test cases to maximize success of manual testing with consistent, thorough approaches.



## **Education**

2005-08 -2009-12

# Bachelor's of Technology: Electronics And Communications Engineering

JNTU - Kakinada



## **Accomplishments**



10 Years of experience in Functional Automation
 Testing & DevOps using Selenium WebDriver,

- Appium, Jenkins.
- Good experience in building pipeline using Git,
   Bitbucket & Jenkins
   Experience in automation of Restful Web Services
   & SOAP web services.
- Experience in creating Data Driven, Keyword
   Driven, and Hybrid Frameworks with TestNG,
   Cucumber and Maven.
- Implemented Remote browser execution using
   Selenium Grid & parallel execution using TestNG.
- Experience in automating mobile apps on Android and iOS using **Appium**
- Experience in writing Generic Scripts and Project Specific Scripts using Java.
- Good knowledge on all stages of SDLC & STLC.
- Performed Smoke Testing, Component Testing, Integration Testing, System Testing, Regression Testing and Compatibility Testing
- Experience in writing test cases in SOAPUI tool for testing SOAP web services.
- Good exposure in Requirements understanding and analyzing.
- Ability to manage multiple projects and tasks concurrently.
- Supervised team of 4 and responsible for delivery from the team.
- Involved in Kick-off meetings with client to gather requirement.



## **Certifications**

2011-02



ISTQB Foundation Level (Cert. No.: ITB-CTFL-0034849)